Part 4. You will hear a professor of philosophy giving a talk on the ancient philosophy of Stoicism.
First, you have some time to look at questions 31 to 40.
Now listen carefully and answer questions 31 to 40.
Ancient philosophy is not just about talking or lecturing or even reading long, dense books.
In fact, it is something people have used throughout history to solve their problems and to achieve their greatest triumphs.
Specifically, I am referring to Stoicism, which in my opinion is the most practical of all philosophies and therefore the most appealing.
Stoicism was founded in ancient Greece by Zeno of Citium in the early 3rd century BC,
but was practiced by the likes of Epictetus, Cato, Seneca and Marcus Aurelius.
Amazingly, we still have access to these ideas,
despite the fact that the most famous Stoics never wrote anything down for publication.
Cato definitely didn't.
Marcus Aurelius never intended his meditations to be anything but personal.
Seneca's letters were, well, letters, and Epictetus's thoughts come to us by way of a note-taking student.
Stoic principles were based on the idea that its followers could have an unshakable happiness in this life,
and the key to achieving this was virtue.
The road to virtue, in turn, lay in understanding that destructive emotions,
like anger and jealousy, are under our conscious control.
They don't have to control us, because we can learn to control them.
In the words of Epictetus,
external events I cannot control,
but the choices I make with regard to them I do control.
The modern-day philosopher and writer Nassim Nicholas Taleb
defines a Stoic as someone who has
a different perspective on experiences
which most of us would see as wholly negative.
A Stoic transforms fear into caution,
pain into transformation,
mistakes into initiation,
and desire into undertaking.
Using this definition as a model,
we can see that throughout the centuries,
Stoicism has been practised in more recent history
by kings, presidents,
artists, writers,
and entrepreneurs.
The founding fathers of the United States
were inspired by the philosophy.
George Washington was introduced to Stoicism
by his neighbours at age 17,
and later put on a play based on the life of Cato
to inspire his men.
Thomas Jefferson kept a copy of Seneca beside his bed.
Writers and artists have also been inspired by the Stoics.
Eugene Delacroix,
the renowned French Romantic artist,
known best for his painting
Liberty Leading the People,
was an ardent Stoic,
referring to it as his consoling religion.
The economist Adam Smith's theories on capitalism
were significantly influenced
by the Stoicism that he studied as a schoolboy
under a teacher who had translated
Marcus Aurelius's works.
Today's political leaders are no different,
with many finding their inspiration
from the ancient texts.
Former US President Bill Clinton
re-reads Marcus Aurelius
every single year,
and many have compared
former President Obama's calm leadership style
to that of Cato.
Wen Jiabao,
the former Prime Minister of China,
claims that meditations
is one of two books
he travels with,
and that he has read it
more than 100 times
over the course of his life.
Stoicism had a profound influence
on Albert Ellis,
who invented
cognitive behaviour therapy,
which is used to help people
manage their problems
by changing the way
that they think and behave.
It's most commonly used
to treat depression.
The idea is that
we can take control of our lives
by challenging the irrational beliefs
that create our faulty thinking,
symptoms,
and behaviours
by using logic instead.
Stoicism
has also become popular
in the world of business.
Stoic principles
can build the resilience
and state of mind
required to overcome setbacks,
because Stoics
teach turning obstacles
into opportunity.
A lesson
every business entrepreneur
needs to learn.
I would argue that
studying Stoicism
is as relevant today
as it was
2,000 years ago,
thanks to its brilliant insights
into how to lead a good life.
At the very root
of the thinking,
there is a very simple
way of living.
Control what you can
and accept
what you can't.
This is not as easy
as it sounds
and will require
considerable practice.
It can take a lifetime
to master.
The Stoics
also believed
the most important
foundation
for a good
and happy life
is not money,
fame,
power,
or pleasure,
but having
a disciplined
and principled
character.
Something which
seems to resonate
with many people
today.
You now have
one minute
to check
your answers
to part 4.
That is the end
of the listening test.
In the IELTS test,
you would now
have 10 minutes
to transfer
your answers
to the answer sheet.
and if you
have a good
complete
approach
because I might